I wanted to save her...
（上条(かみじょう)）
俺は あいつを助けたかった
...not fight her.
戦うのではなく ただ 助けたかった
I just wanted to save her.
ただ それだけの話だ
That was all.
（美琴(みこと)）
死ぬわよ
You're gonna die.
今度の一撃をまともに食らったら
あんたは絶対に生きられない
Eat this one head on, and you won't be able to live for sure.
～♪
#13 Accelerator
One-Way Road
（御坂(みさか)10032）
利用地形は
絶対座標 Ｘ-228561 Ｙ-568714
"Absolute coordinates for battlefield terrain are X-228561 by Y-568714."
"Starting time is 8:30 p.m. exact, Japan Standard Time."
開始時刻は
日本標準時 午後８時30分ジャスト
"Test material to be used will be no. 10032."
使用検体は10032号
"Test purpose will be to develop maneuvers for battles where 'reflection' cannot be used."
その用途は 反射を
適応できない戦闘における対処法
Who are you?
（上条）
お前は誰なんだ？
お前は何をやってるんだ？
What are you doing?
"I don't know."
分からない　理解ができません
"I cannot understand," as MISAKA suspects the mental condition of the young man.
…と ミサカは
少年の心理状態に疑問を抱きます
"Yet, why is it that MISAKA is recalling his face now?"
なのに なぜ あの少年の顔を
思い出したのでしょう？
RSPK syndrome, or what is commonly referred to as poltergeist,
（小萌(こもえ)）
ＲＳＰＫ症候群
俗にいうポルターガイストは―
is caused by children who cannot perceive reality properly due to mental trauma or heavy stress.
心的外傷や過度のストレスにより
正しく現実を見ることが
できなくなった子供たちが―
引き起こすものですし
In the experiments for "skill development",
能力開発に用いる実験の中には
さまざまな方法を使って―
various methods have been used to "separate" one from normal reality.
通常の現実から
切り離すものもあります
（小萌）
まともな現実から
切り離された超能力者は―
An esper that is separated from proper reality will be able to obtain their own unique "personal reality".
私たちと異なる自分だけの現実を
手に入れます
As a result, under rules different from those of normal humans, they can distort the world,
（小萌）
その結果 常人とは異なる法則で
ミクロの世界をゆがめ―
or destroy things without physically touching them,
手も触れずに物を破壊したり
or read into the future one year hence just by closing their eyes, etc. and acquire such powers.
瞳を閉じるだけで １年後の未来が
読めたりといった―
力を手に入れることができるのです
（３人）
プハァ～ッ…
What is referred to as "skill development" in Academy City denotes this act of artificially creating one's "personal reality".
学園都市で
行われている能力開発とは―
人為的に自分だけの現実を
作ることを指します
Basically, with the help of drugs and hypnosis, we cause a certain type of change in the brain.
簡単に言えば
薬物や暗示などを使い―
脳に ある種の変化を
起こす手伝いをしているんです
That is why, by ingesting a certain amount of "curriculum", all people would awaken esper abilities.
だから
一定のカリキュラムを消化すれば
誰でも必ず目覚めるはずなのです
But somehow...
にもかかわらず…
...someone who didn't awaken to any power came along...
（姫神(ひめがみ)）
何の力も目覚めない人がいたりして
...like Kamijyo Touma...
上条当麻(とうま)とか
う～ん… いや　むしろ
上条ちゃんみたいなタイプのほうが
Actually... people like Kamijyo-chan are more significant...
重要なんですけどね
あっ 当麻の力を知ってるの？
Do you know Touma's power?
Well, Kamijyo-chan has been a bit of a naughty boy since he enrolled.
まあ 上条ちゃんは―
入学したころから
やんちゃでしたからね
A lot of things happened... A lot...
いろいろあったのですよ いろいろ
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）またか
（姫神）あの野郎
Another one?
That bastard.
The fact that Level 0's exist means there are still rules we haven't been able to explain yet.
レベル０(ゼロ)が存在するってことは
つまり―
まだ解明されていない法則が
あるってことですから
それこそが“SYSTEM(システム)”に
つながるカギかもしれないのです
That could be the key to SYSTEM, which means "those who aren't deities that reach the sense of the heavens".
“神ならぬ身にて 天上の意思に
たどりつく者”という意味です
We still don't know the truth about the world.
私たちには
世界の真理は分かりません
But to find the answer is easy;
ならば 話は簡単で
if someone appears with a status superior to humans,
this person would be able to understand God's answers.
人間以上のステータスを持つ者が
現れれば―
神さまの答えだって
理解できるに決まってるのです
よいしょっと…
ふ～ん… 神さまの答えか
God's answers, huh?
My... hand...
（上条）
俺の手…
Was I out cold?
気ぃ失っていたのか
What happened?
何があったんだっけか
Ah, I remember.
ああ　そうか
What are you doing...
何やってんのよ？　あんた
そんなにボロボロになって
汚い地面の上に転がって
Getting yourself all hurt...
Rolling around on this dirty concrete...
（美琴）
心臓だって
止まってたかもしれないのに
Your heart might've even stopped, too...
なんで… なんで
そんな顔で笑ってられんのよ？
Why... can you even be smiling like that?
I know now.
（上条）分かったんだ
（美琴）えっ？
I know how to stop the experiment now.
実験を止める方法が分かったんだ
It's pretty easy if you think about it.
考えてみれば
簡単だったんじゃねえか
Tree Diagram designed the experiment under the assumption that Accelerator is the strongest esper in Academy City.
（上条）
樹形図の設計者(ツリーダイアグラム)は 当然―
アクセラレータが
学園都市最強って前提で―
実験をプログラムしたんだろう
So, for example, if the so-called strongest Accelerator was beaten in a street fight,
そう　例えば 最強ってうたってる
アクセラレータが―
なんてことのないケンカで
簡単に倒されたら？
前提条件が崩れた実験を
続けるヤツはいねえだろう
no one would continue an experiment where
the underlying assumptions don't hold anymore.
だったら 研究者たちに
こう思い込ませればいい
So we just need to let those scientists think that.
“実は アクセラレータって
メチャクチャ弱かったんだな”って
That Accelerator is really super weak.
That's not possible.
ムリよ そんなの
I've met Accelerator face-to-face only once.
私が直接アクセラレータってヤツと
顔を合わせたのは１度だけ
But I could tell.
でも 分かる
A battle with him wouldn't even be called a match.
（美琴）
あいつとの戦いは もう
勝ち負けの混在する勝負じゃない
A battle, to him, is just a one-way road of slaughtering his opponent.
あいつにとって 戦うってのは―
ただ一方的に
相手を虐殺するってことなんだから
Besides, both he and I are Level 5.
それに
私も あいつと同じレベル５(ファイブ)なのよ
Even if I were to miraculously defeat him,
奇跡的に私が勝ったとしても―
those scientists will conclude that it was within the error range.
研究者たちは誤差の範囲ってことで
話をつけてしまう
They won't be able to think that Accelerator was actually weak.
“アクセラレータが実は弱かった”
…なんてふうには思わないわよ
Then, if I fight, it'll be perfect.
（上条）
それなら…
（上条）俺が戦えばいいんだろう？
（美琴）えっ？
（上条）
学園都市最強のレベル５が―
If the strongest Level 5 in Academy City...
...lost to the weakest Level 0...
学園都市最弱のレベル０に
あっさり敗北したら？
What do you think you're doing?
（美琴）
何やってんの？　あんた
It's impossible.
ムリよ　あんたは
アクセラレータの力が分かってない
You don't know Accelerator's powers.
世界中の軍隊を敵に回しても
平気っていうようなヤツと―
The fact you're trying to fight someone who wouldn't flinch at the thought of...
正面から戦おうなんて考えが
もう おかしいんだってば
...taking on the entire world's military straight up is already insane, okay?!
Momentum, heat, electric charge,
あいつは 運動量 熱量 電気量
あらゆる種類のベクトルを―
any kind of vector that he comes in touch with, he can manipulate!
触れただけで操ることができる
Forget the fact that none of your attacks will reach him,
（美琴）
こっちからの攻撃は
届かないばかりか―
全て反射して戻ってくるの
he'll just counter them back at you.
To take on a rule breaker like that face on...
そんな はなから反則な人間に
正面から ぶつかったって…
And look at you, you're all beat up!
まして あんたは
そんなにボロボロじゃない
そんな状況で
あんなバケモノに勝てるはずがない
There's no way you can defeat that monster!
（美琴）
どうして…
Why...
（上条）
お前は もともと―
You were going to Accelerator's location originally, right?
アクセラレータの所に
行こうとしてたんだよな？
Tell me.
（上条）教えろ
（美琴）えっ…
Where is he?
あいつは どこにいる？
Current time is 8:25, isn't it?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
時刻は８時25分ってとこか？
じゃ お前が 次の実験の―
That must mean that you're the next target in the experiment, I take it?
ターゲットってことで
かまわねえんだな？
"Yes."
（御坂10032）
はい　ミサカのシリアルナンバーは
10032号です
"MISAKA's serial number is 10032," answers MISAKA.
…と ミサカは返答します
"Before that, isn't it more appropriate to say the password to confirm participation in the experiment?" advises MISAKA.
その前に 実験関係者かどうか
パスを確かめるのが妥当では？
…と ミサカは助言します
Well, you realize I don't really have to confirm anything because it's an experiment that's trying to make me stronger...
まあ 俺が強くなるための実験に
つきあわせてる身で―
言えた義理じゃねえんだけどさ
But you sure look calm knowing your situation...
よく平然としてるよな この状況で
ちっとは何か考えたりしねえのか？
Can't you use your brain a little?
“何か”という曖昧な表現では
分かりかねます
"A vague term such as 'a little' prevents MISAKA from understanding," replies MISAKA.
…と ミサカは返答します
"There are three minutes and twenty seconds before the experiment begins,"
実験開始まで３分20秒ですが
準備は整っているのですか？
"but are you finished with your preparations?" confirms MISAKA.
…と ミサカは確認を取ります
自分の命をなげうつなんざ
俺には理解できねえな
Because I can't fathom the first bit of throwing my own life away.
俺は自分の命が いちばんだしさ
My life is what's most important to me.
だからこそ
力を欲することに際限はねえし
That's why my desire for more power has no limits.
そのためなら お前たちが
何百 何千 何万と死のうが―
That's why no matter how many hundreds, thousands, or tens of thousands of you die,
知ったこっちゃねえって
鼻で笑うこともできんだぜ
I'll be laughing hard, saying "like I care".
ミサカのほうこそ あなたの言動に
理解できない部分があります
"Neither does MISAKA understand some of your actions," answers MISAKA.
…と ミサカは答えます
"You are already the strongest Level 5 in Academy City."
あなたは 既に
学園都市で最強のレベル５です
"Since you are already in a position where no one can catch you,"
誰も追いつけない位置に
立っているならば―
"why is it necessary to desire more power?" supposes MISAKA.
それ以上の力を
欲する必要はないのでは？
…と ミサカは予測します
Strongest, eh?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
最強ね
Well, how do people know that?
そんじゃ どうして
周りの連中は それを知ってんだ？
Because they actually fought me and lost, right?
実際に俺と戦ってみて
負けたからだろう？
In other words, my strength is only at the level of "fun"...
of "let's try picking a fight with him"...
逆に言えば 俺の強さは―
“面白そうだから 試しに
あいつにケンカを売ってみよう”
…て程度にしか
思われてねえってことだよな？
ダメだよな そんなんじゃ
I don't like that, got it?
Not a single bit...
全然ダメだ
そんな最強じゃ 全くつまんねえ
That kind of "strongest" is completely worthless!
俺が目指してんのは
その先なんだよ
I strive for something beyond that,
that challenging me would be
the most ridiculous thought ever,
挑戦しようと思うことが
ばかばかしくなるくらいの―
that fighting me would be a sin.
戦おうって思うことすら
許されねえほどの―
そんな無敵な存在なんだよ
I strive for that "absolute" nature!
"There is one minute and thirty seconds before the experiment begins,"
実験開始まで１分30秒ですが
準備は整っていますか？
"but are you finished with your preparations?" reconfirms MISAKA.
…と ミサカは再度 確認をします
Great.
…たく　ちっとは暇でも
つぶしてみようと考えたんだが
I wanted to kill some time, but that doesn't seem possible.
こりゃダメだな
I can't talk with you at all.
やっぱ お前とは会話になんねえわ
そんじゃ もういいか？
Then, are you ready?
そろそろ死んじまえよ
出来損ないの乱造品
It's about time you die.
You worthless piece of excess product.
"8:29:45..."
午後８時29分45秒
"Experiment no. 10032 shall now begin."
これより
第10032次実験を開始します
"Subject 'Accelerator', please move to your designated position," orders MISAKA.
被験者 アクセラレータは
所定の位置に就いてください
…と ミサカは伝令します
（美琴）
西の外れの工業地帯
The industrial area in the western outskirts.
The train switch yard there is the location of the 10032nd experiment.
そこにある列車の操車場が
１万32回目の実験場よ
"The MISAKA that you have been in touch with is Serial Number 10032. This MISAKA."
（御坂10032）
あなたが
今日まで接してきたミサカは―
シリアルナンバー10032
つまり このミサカです
どうしたの？
What's the matter?
そっか… 私の体から電磁波が
Oh, right.
The voltage coming from my body.
He's such an idiot.
バカみたい
You want to save them, then leave this to me.
あいつらを助けたけりゃ
ここは俺に任せてくれ
The crucial point is that I, a Level 0,
beat Accelerator all by myself, right?
大事なのは レベル０の俺が―
１人でアクセラレータを
倒すってことだろう
レベル５のお前が一緒に戦っちゃ
話にならないだろう
For a Level 5 to be fighting with me would just ruin everything.
I will...
絶対に…
絶対に連れて帰ってくるから
I will...
I will bring her back...
I know, okay?!
分かってるわよ
確かに 私が あそこに行ったって
何にもできない
I won't be able to do anything even if I go there.
けど
…んなことができると思ってんの？
But, you think I can just stand here?!
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
何だよ　何だ　何ですか？
What? What? What is this?
No matter how much time you buy for yourself,
どれだけ時間を稼いだところで…
miracles won't happen!
奇跡なんざ
起きるわきゃねえだろう！
"This night..."
（御坂10032）
今夜は…
"...has no wind"
今夜は風がないのですね
あっ… このにおい
This smell...
Oh, I see...
はぁ… なるほどね
電気で酸素を分解して
オゾンにしてるってわけか
You're using electrons to break up
oxygen and create ozone.
Trying to make me run out of air, huh?
この俺を
酸欠状態に持ち込もうってか？
Wonderful, wonderful!
いいね いいね！　最高だね！
Absolutely wonderful!
Serving as my enemy rather well, eh?
きっちり 俺の敵やってんじゃん！
退屈しねえな
This does not bore me.
さすがに １万回も殺されりゃ―
You do get smarter after getting killed ten thousand times, eh?
悪知恵のひとつでも
はたらくってか？
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
だけど 弱点が ひとつ
But there's a weak point in this.
If I catch you, then this plan will fail, eh?
お前が追いつかれちまったら
この作戦は失敗だよな？
驚くことはねえだろう
Don't act surprised.
足の裏にかかる運動量のベクトルを
変えただけだ
I just changed the vectors behind my feet.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
なあ　自分の手を痛めずに
相手を殴る方法って知ってっか？
Hey...
Do you know of a method of beating your opponent without hurting your own knuckles?
相手の体が触れた瞬間
The second you touch the other person's body,
change the vector of the opposing momentum towards that person.
運動量のベクトルを
相手に向けりゃいいんだよ
その分
相手のダメージは倍になるけどな
Well, your opponent gets twice the amount of pain, but...
おい　この場合 実験ってのは
どうなっちまうんだ？
Hey, what happens to the experiment in this situation?
離れろよ てめえ
今すぐ御坂妹から離れろ
Get away from her.
You get away from Misaka's sister right now.
Hey, hey, come on now.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
おいおい　頼むぜ
Don't bring a civilian to the experiment grounds.
一般人なんざ
実験場に連れ込んでんじゃねえよ
Man, this'll leave a bad taste.
くそ　後味悪いな
Gotta kill off civilians that find out about the secret, right?
秘密を知った一般人の口は
封じるとかってお決まりの展開か？
Shut up.
（上条）うるせえよ…
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）ああ？
グチャグチャ言ってないで
離れろっつってんだろう 三下(さんした)！
Quit talking nonsense and get away from her, I said.
You thug!
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
お前 何さま？
And who do you think you are?
７人しかいねえレベル５の
超能力者の中でも―
Calling me, the strongest of only seven Level 5 espers, a thug?
頂点って呼ばれてる
この俺に向かって “三下”？
フッ… 笑えねえ
It's not even funny.
Hey, you're kind of fun.
へえ… お前 面白(おもしれ)えな
"What are you..."
（御坂10032）
何を…
何をやっているんですかと…
"What are you doing..." asks MISAKA...
（御坂10032）
ミサカは問いかけます
Oh, it's the sister.
（上条）
なんだ　妹のほうか
You really are the spitting image of Mikoto.
お前 ホントに 美琴に似てるよな
Yo, thanks for the juice and fleas yesterday.
ウッス！　昨日は
ジュースとノミの件 サンキューな
お前が拾ったんだから
せめて名前ぐらい お前が付けろよ
Hey, you picked it up, at least give it a name.
"MISAKA doubts her own mental status."
ミサカは
自分の心理状態に疑問を抱きます
"For a clone that has as many replacements as desired,"
いくらでも
替えを作れる模造品のために―
"what are you trying to do for MISAKA?" asks MISAKA once again.
あなたは
何をしようとしているのですか？
…と ミサカは
再三にわたって問いかけます
ミサカは ボタンひとつで
いくらでも自動生産できるんです
"MISAKA can be automatically reproduced countless times at the push of a button."
作り物の体に 借り物の心
"A manufactured body borrowing a heart."
在庫にして 9,968も…
"There are still 9,968 in stock-"
（上条）
うるせえよ
Shut up.
ちっせえ事情なんか
知ったことじゃねえ
Like I care about all those little details.
I am standing here to save you.
俺は お前を助けるために
ここに立ってんだよ
お前は 世界で
たったひとりしかいねえだろうが
There's only one of you in this world, isn't there?!
勝手に死ぬんじゃねえぞ
Don't be dying on me like that, okay?
I have plenty of things I want to give you an earful on, okay?
お前には
まだ文句が山ほど残ってんだ
今から お前を助けてやる
So, I'm going to save you now.
You just shut up and lie there.
お前は黙って そこで見てろ
（握りしめる音）
What?
なんだ？
Letting out all those heroic lines like that...
さっきから ヒーローじみたセリフ
ペラペラ ペラペラ
まさか この俺の存在
忘れちまったんじゃねえよな？
Don't tell me you forgot about my presence, eh?
（上条）アッ！
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）遅(おせ)えなぁ
Too slow.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
お前 そんな速度じゃ
100年遅えっつってんだよ！
With that speed, you're a whole century too slow!
Come on, come on!
Too slow.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
遅えなぁ
ほら　全然 遅え
Come on, you're way too slow.
狩人を楽しませるなら
キツネになれ
You want me to enjoy this hunt, then become a fox.
Don't be a pig that's waiting to be devoured, thug!
食われるためのブタで
止まってんじゃねえぞ 三下！
Well then.
さてと…
ウワッ！
Shall we... put an end to this?
そろそろ 終わりにするとすっか
Huh?
中身は小麦粉でしたってな
Looks like it was wheat flour inside.
へえ… 今日は 風もねえし
And since there's no wind tonight,
this might be a rather dangerous circumstance, eh?
こりゃ ひょっとすると
危険な状態かもしんねえな
なんでも 空気中に粉末が漂ってて
そいつに火がつくとさ
Because, there's powdery stuff floating in the air,
and if it caught fire...
...I bet the speed at which oxygen burns would be crazy fast!
酸素の燃焼速度が
バカみてえに早くなるんだと
なあ　お前
You've heard of "dust explosions" at least, right?
粉塵(ふんじん)爆発って言葉ぐれえ
聞いたことあるよな？
～♪
Next Episode
（上条）
世界で たったひとりの
お前のために 一体 何ができる？
For the one and only you in this world,
what can I do?
I can't even get near him,
ヤツに近づけもしない最弱の俺に
me, the weakest esper.
次回 「最弱 VS(対) 最強」
Next time, "Weakest vs. Strongest".
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる
When science and magic cross paths,
this epic will begin!